<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" standalone="no"?>

<!DOCTYPE document SYSTEM '../../common/dtd/objectweb.dtd'>

<document>
  <properties>
    <author email="javaservice@objectweb.org">javaservice team</author>
    <title>Background</title>
    <filename>background.xml</filename>
    <pathtoroot>.</pathtoroot>
  </properties>

  <body>

    <s1 name="Background">

	<subtitle>Alexandria Version</subtitle>
	<p>The JavaService system service utility was originally developed and made available by
	Alexandria Software Consulting, under a BSD-style license (from the web site at
	www.alexandriasc.com - no longer reachable). The last version from that
	source was V1.2.0 and this has been widely used for many applications.</p>

	<subtitle>Multiplan Versions</subtitle>
	<p>Multiplan Consultants subsequently made a range of enhancements to the software,
	continuing to make these updates available under the same licensing terms. Three
	incremental releases have been provided (1.2.1, 1.2.2 and 1.2.3) from the software
	section of the <a href="http://www.multiplan.co.uk/software/javaservice">www.multiplan.co.uk</a> web site.</p>
	
	<subtitle>ObjectWeb Versions</subtitle>
	<p>JavaService has now been accepted as an ObjectWeb project and is hosted on the Forge section of that site.
	The project administrator at this time is John Rutter, of Multiplan Consultants, so this does provide for a
	level of continuity from the updates of previous years.</p>

	<p>Ongoing development of the software incorporates further enhancements and functionality.
	The community features of the ObjectWeb Forge
	allows for easier exchange of comments and ideas relating to the project.
	<br />
	For all releases of JavaService from the ObjectWeb project, the 
	<a href="http://www.gnu.org/copyleft/lesser.html">GNU Lesser General Public License</a> (LGPL) now applies.</p>

	<p>Further, it is the intention that the JavaService utility will be the preferred method to be used by all ObjectWeb
	projects when they are installed and used on a Windows NT-type system. It is hoped that this adoption over time will
	make for consistent ease-of-use of other ObjectWeb projects and also lead to further improvements to JavaService itself.
	</p>
    </s1>
    
  </body>
  
</document>
