<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" standalone="no"?>

<!DOCTYPE document SYSTEM '../../common/dtd/objectweb.dtd'>

<document>
  <properties>
    <author email="javaservice@objectweb.org">javaservice team</author>
    <title>Contributions</title>
    <filename>contribute.xml</filename>
    <pathtoroot>.</pathtoroot>
  </properties>

  <body>

    <s1 name="User Contributions">

	<subtitle>Are you using JavaService?</subtitle>

	<p>If you make use of the JavaService utility, then why not share that information?
	Send an email to the <a href="mailto:javaservice@objectweb.org">javaservice team</a> and describe what you are using it for.
	The more user stories that can be described for the software, then the better the likelihood of future enhancements,
	better shared support, and increased future take-up.</p>

    </s1>
    
    <s1 name="Developer Contributions">

	<subtitle>Enhancements for JavaService</subtitle>
	<p>If you have developed any improvements or new features to the JavaService C++ software, it would be greatly
	appreciated if you would share these with the greater Open Source community. Send in your updates and they will
	be considered for inclusion in subsequent releases, or made available for manual add-ins if desired.</p>

	<subtitle>JavaService Documentation</subtitle>
	<p>Although the software itself is easy to use, any application can benefit from further documentation effort to
	describe configuration, usage and frequently-asked-questions. Any input on this front will be appreciated.</p>

	<subtitle>Test Tools</subtitle>
	<p>As some people do experience occasional problems with their installations of JavaService, it can be useful to
	have a standard test tool application that can be loaded into a user environment. An initial version has
	been developed for investigation of one particular fault (a JVM was leaking memory when run as a service), but a
	clearer set of test software would be helpful. If you have, or wish to write, Java software of this sort then
	please do contact the team to see what may be the best route to take.</p>

    </s1>

    <s1 name="Previous Contributors">

	<p>The JavaService software exists due to contributions from the following:</p>
	
	<ul>
		<li>E Roberts, Alexandria Software Consulting</li>
		<li>Anthony Tagunov</li>
		<li>Joe Siebenmann</li>
		<li>Lars Johanson</li>
		<li>James Bigler</li>
		<li>John Rutter, Multiplan Consultants</li>
	</ul>

    </s1>

  </body>
  
</document>
